<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on ThapeloOnTheRun</title>
    <link>https://example.com/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on ThapeloOnTheRun</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Regaining confidence</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blogs/confidence-boost-24-11-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blogs/confidence-boost-24-11-2024/</guid>
      <description>As the training progressed, I ticked off a few confidence-boosting long runs. I can attribute the success of these long runs to two aspects of training.&#xA;Improving fitness Nutrition (Before and during long runs) Improving fitness A few weeks of building up led to the longest run of 12 km in late September with an average running week volume of 32 km in the same month. Now, it was time to push up some mileage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slowly building back</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blogs/continuing-the-build-22-09-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blogs/continuing-the-build-22-09-2024/</guid>
      <description>Few weeks have gone by without any update.&#xA;Training As mentioned above, I did a 12 week based building structured as:&#xA;Week # Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday Saturday Sunday Total 1 Rest 8 km Easy run Rest 8 km Easy run Rest 10 km Easy run 6 km Easy run 32 km 2 Rest 10 km Easy run Rest 8 km Easy run Rest 10 km Easy run 8 km Easy run 35 km 3 Rest 8 km Easy run 6 km Easy run 8 km Easy run Rest 10 km Easy run 8 km Easy run 40 km 4 Rest 8 km Easy run 6 km Easy run 8 km Easy run Rest 10 km Easy run + 4 x 100 m strides 8 km Easy run 40 km 5 Rest 8 km Easy run + 4 x 100 m strides 6 km Easy run 8 km Easy run + 4 x 100 m strides Rest 11 km Long run (Easy) 7 km Easy run + 4 x 100 m strides 40 km 6 Rest 10 km Easy run + 4 x 100 m strides 8 km Easy run 10 km Easy run + 4 x 100 m strides Rest 12 km Long run (Easy) 8 km Easy run + 4 x 100 m strides 48 km 7 Rest 8 km Easy run 11 km 3 km warm up + 4 x 100 m strides 20 min @ Tempo 3 km Cool down 8 km Recovery run Rest 13 km Long run Easy + Hilly route 8 km Recovery run 4 x 100 m Strides 48 km 8 Rest 8 km Easy run 11 km 3 km warm up Fartlek 10 x 1 min-fast, 1 min-easy 3 km Cool down 8 km Recovery run Rest 13 km Long run Progression 8 km Recovery run 4 x 100 m Strides 48 km 9 Rest 11 km Easy run 6 km Easy run + 4 x 100 m strides 11 km Easy run + 4 x 100 m strides 8 km Recovery run 14 km Long run Easy 6 km Recovery run 4 x 100 m Strides 56 km 10 Rest 8 km Easy run + 4 x 100 m strides 11 km 3 km warm up + 4 x 100 m strides 20 min @ Tempo 3 km Cool down 8 km Recovery run 8 km Easy run 15 km Long run Easy + Hilly route 6 km Recovery run + 4 x 100 m strides 56 km 11 Rest 8 km Easy run + 4 x 100 m strides 11 km 3 km warm up Fartlek 10 x 1 min-fast, 1 min-easy 3 km Cool down 8 km Recovery run 8 km Easy run 15 km Long run Progression 6 km Recovery run + 4 x 100 m strides 56 km 12 Rest 11 km Easy run + 4 x 100 m strides 10 km Recovery run 11 km Easy run + 4 x 100 m strides 8 km Recovery run 16 km Long run Easy 8 km Recovery run + 4 x 100 m strides 64 km Credit to the plan is given to https://knightonruns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building back - Week 1</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blogs/base-building-11-08-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blogs/base-building-11-08-2024/</guid>
      <description>Week 1 - Base Building I have decided to do my training on a softer surface. Not a bad idea, I might keep this for a while. I completed four (4) runs during the first week of running outdoors and one (1) cross-training session. Here is the summary in a Table below&#xA;04 to 11 August 2024 Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday Saturday Sunday Total 30 min @ Easy Rest 30 min @ Easy 30 min @ Easy Rest 45 min @ Easy 30 min Indoor cycling 2:15:49 (excl.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting back - Week 2</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blogs/getting-back-04-08-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blogs/getting-back-04-08-2024/</guid>
      <description>Following a good week one of getting back, it was now the time to extend the time spend on feet. Week 2 of getting back included 3 runs with the longest being the first continous 30 minutes easy run.&#xA;This is how week 2 of getting back went.&#xA;Week 2 29 July to 04 August 2024 Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday Saturday Sunday Rest 5 min walk 20 min Jog 5 min walk Rest 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting back - Test runs</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blogs/getting-back-28-07-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blogs/getting-back-28-07-2024/</guid>
      <description>After eight weeks of no running, it was the time to test if the stress fracture is healed. I decided to do Treadmill running every other day for first few runs post the injury. This is how week 1 went.&#xA;Week 1 22 to 28 July 2024 Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday Saturday Sunday 3 sets of (2 min Jog&#xA;8 min Walk) Rest 3 sets of (4min Jog&#xA;6 min Walk) Rest 3 sets of (6 min Jog</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thapelo is Injured</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blogs/stressfracture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blogs/stressfracture/</guid>
      <description>Thapelo got INJURED&#xA;Official diagnosis - Stress Fracture (Right Fibula)&#xA;A few runs post my Half-marathon PB, I started feeling a slight pain in my lower leg. The pain was not there when I walked and ran, I could only feel it when I pressed hard around the injured area. I figured that it was just a niggle that will go away.&#xA;I proceeded to run another half-marathon on the 1st of May 2024 (Official time - 1:50:15).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half-marathon PB - BNAC</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blogs/half-marathonpb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blogs/half-marathonpb/</guid>
      <description>Preparation for this race followed a 10 km race (Urithi legacy) I had just done on the 4th of February 2024. I did the race with a finish time of 50:15 (Horrible race). The half marathon was scheduled for the 21st of April 2024. I had about 11 weeks to prepare.&#xA;Training For this training block, I ran an average of 5 days a week. The training block was disrupted a few times because of my international travels and family commitments but such is life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 k PB - Growthpoint Sundowner 10km</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blogs/10kpb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blogs/10kpb/</guid>
      <description>After months of inconsistent running and injuries, I discovered the phrases &amp;ldquo;BASE BUILDING&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;STRENGTH TRAINING&amp;rdquo;. In the preceding few months, I had suffered from shin splints and soleus muscle injuries after I had discovered &amp;ldquo;SANCTIONED RACES&amp;rdquo;. I fell into the trap of overdoing pretty much everything (i.e. &amp;ldquo;training&amp;rdquo; and racing). By training I mean some random running, once every other day. Basically, go out and run as fast as you possibly can all the time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 k PB - Growthpoint Sundowner 10km</title>
      <link>https://example.com/blogs/training-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/blogs/training-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>After months of inconsistent running and injuries, I discovered the phrases &amp;ldquo;BASE BUILDING&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;STRENGTH TRAINING&amp;rdquo;. In the preceding few months, I had suffered from shin splints and soleus muscle injuries after I had discovered &amp;ldquo;SANCTIONED RACES&amp;rdquo;. I fell into the trap of overdoing pretty much everything (i.e. &amp;ldquo;training&amp;rdquo; and racing). By training I mean some random running, once every other day. Basically, go out and run as fast as you possibly can all the time.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
